<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Graham Essays</title>
    <link>https://paulgraham.com/feed_paulgraham.xml</link>
    <description>Paul Graham's Essays and Writings</description>
    <atom:link href="https://paulgraham.com/feed_paulgraham.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 20:41:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>When To Do What You Love</title>
      <link>https://paulgraham.com/when.html</link>
      <description>There's some debate about whether it's a good idea to "follow your
passion." In fact the question is impossible to answer with a simple
yes or no. Sometimes you should and sometimes you shouldn't, but
the border between should and shouldn't is very complicated. The
only way to give a general answer is to trace it.When people talk about this question, there's always an implicit
"instead of." All other things being equal, why wouldn't you work
on what interests you the most? So even raising the qu...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paulgraham.com/when.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writes and Write-Nots</title>
      <link>https://paulgraham.com/writes.html</link>
      <description>I'm usually reluctant to make predictions about technology, but I
feel fairly confident about this one: in a couple decades there
won't be many people who can write.One of the strangest things you learn if you're a writer is how
many people have trouble writing. Doctors know how many people have
a mole they're worried about; people who are good at setting up
computers know how many people aren't; writers know how many people
need help writing.The reason so many people have trouble writing is tha...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paulgraham.com/writes.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Lose Time and Money</title>
      <link>https://paulgraham.com/selfindulgence.html</link>
      <description>When we sold our startup in 1998 I suddenly got a lot of money.  I
now had to think about something I hadn't had to think about before:
how not to lose it.   I knew it was possible to go from rich to
poor, just as it was possible to go from poor to rich.  But while
I'd spent a lot of the past several years studying the paths from
poor to rich, 
I knew practically nothing about the paths from rich
to poor.  Now, in order to avoid them, I had to learn where they
were.So I started to pay attention ...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://paulgraham.com/selfindulgence.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
